https://oaltabo.on.ca/about/privacy-policy/

Privacy Policy – OALT/ABO
Home
Contact
About Us
What is a Technician?
My Account
Welcome to the Ontario Association of Library Technicians / Association des bibliotechniciens de l’Ontario
Menu
Home
Contact
About Us
What is a Technician?
Privacy Policy
INTRODUCTION:
The Ontario Association of Library Technicians/Association des bibliotechniciens de l’Ontario (OALT/ABO)’s Privacy Policy is designed to provide details about how we safeguard the privacy, confidentiality and security of your personal information.
PURPOSE:
Why does the OALT/ABO need to collect information about you? Simply, we collect personal information about you in order to serve you properly, to develop programs and services for you and your peers, to facilitate the volunteer activities of this Association, and to help you communicate with your fellow members. We never collect more information about you than is necessary for these purposes and you always have the right to refuse the information requested.
PROCEDURES:
What information about you do we collect?
Personal and other information you choose to provide in membership and registration forms.
Information you provide in emails or contact forms that you send us.
Personal information you provide in response to surveys and other research tools.
Transaction information necessary to maintain an accurate business relationship with you that is open and transparent for auditors to determine the correctness and fairness of our dealings with you and you with us.
What do we do with your personal information?
We use your personal information:
to properly identify you;
to serve your professional needs;
to establish your membership and to maintain, record and store your membership information;
to execute transactions;
to provide you with ongoing services;
to develop and offer additional products and services we feel may be of interest to you; and
to meet our legal and regulatory requirements under Canadian law
With whom is your information shared?
OALT/ABO is not in the business of selling or distributing our members’ personal information to others. Nor do we allow access to internal communication by outside groups. Member confidentiality and privacy remains a fundamental principle of ours. However, we may share your information with others outside OALT/ABO in certain limited circumstances including:
With Third Party Suppliers whom we hire to perform services on our and your behalf. We provide them with a limited amount of information in order that they may provide services including, but not limited to accounting,  research approved by the OALT/ABO Board of Directors, products and services developed for member benefit, and our own market research. They are prohibited from using information for purposes other than to carry out the service they have been engaged or approved to provide. These third party suppliers are not permitted to disclose this information to others. Sharing this information with these third parties is critical to OALT/ABO providing you with the best service possible and with carrying out the Association’s mandate.
When Permitted or Required by Law. OALT/ABO is compelled to disclose personal information in response to a law, regulation, court order, subpoena, valid demand, search warrant or other legally valid request or enquiry. We may disclose information to our accountants, auditors, agents and lawyers in connection with the enforcement or protection of our legal rights. We may disclose information to various regulators in order to comply with regulatory requirements to which we are subject. This helps ensure honest and ethical business practices.
How is your information protected?
Your information is held in a pass code-protected database and is only available for use by select OALT/ABO Board Members in the conduct of the Association’s regular business.
What privacy rights do you have?
You may request access to your personal information that we hold. You may question the accuracy and completeness of this information. You may opt out or withdraw your consent that allows us to share your personal information in certain circumstances. You may withdraw consent given at any time by contracting us by email or postal mail at the addresses noted below. However, your decision to withdraw or revoke your consent may limit the products or services that we are able to provide to you.
Who do you contact about privacy concerns at the OALT/ABO?
If you have any questions or concerns about our Privacy Policy you may contact the OALT/ABO President as follows:
President, Board of Directors
Ontario Association of Library Technicians/Association des bibliotechniciens de l’Ontario
Abbey Market, P.O. Box 76010, 1500 Upper Middle Road West,
Oakville, ON, L6M 3H5
Email: president@oaltabo.on.ca
ADDITIONAL INFORMATION
Cookies
A cookie is a small computer file or piece of information that may be stored in your computer's hard drive when you visit our websites. We may use cookies to improve our website’s functionality and in some cases, to provide visitors with a customized online experience.
Cookies are widely used and most web browsers are configured initially to accept cookies automatically. You may change your Internet browser settings to prevent your computer from accepting cookies or to notify you when you receive a cookie so that you may decline its acceptance. Please note, however, if you disable cookies, you may not experience optimal performance of our website.
Other Websites
Our website may contain links to other third party sites that are not governed by this privacy policy. Although we endeavour to only link to sites with high privacy standards, our privacy policy will no longer apply once you leave our website. Additionally, we are not responsible for the privacy practices employed by third party websites. Therefore, we suggest that you examine the privacy statements of those sites to learn how your information may be collected, used, shared and disclosed.
Date Approved: August 14, 2017
© 2020 Ontario Association of Library Technicians/Association des bibliotechniciens de l'Ontario
Abbey Market, P.O. Box 76010, 1500 Upper Middle Road West, Oakville, ON, L6M 3H5
email: info@oaltabo.on.ca
Web Development The Ian Scott Group
